AdrenergicQuestions1 = [
    {
        "question": "Drugs that affect receptors stimulated by ____ or ____ are adrenergic and may block neurotransmission (s____) and may interrupt release of norepinephrine from neuron",
        "answer": "NE, E, sympatholytic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a1 is ____ and affects s____ muscle constriction",
        "answer": "postsynaptic, smooth",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a2 is largely p____ autoreceptor, feedback inhibition",
        "answer": "presynaptic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "____ is primarily cardiac muscle",
        "answer": "B1",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "____ is found in bronchi and vascular smooth muscle",
        "answer": "B2",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "____ is metabolic responses to adipocytes",
        "answer": "B3",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adrenergic receptors belong to superfamily of ____",
        "answer": "GPCR",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a1 agonist leads to v____, i____ peripheral resistance, i____ blood pressure, m____, and i____ closure of internal sphincter of bladder",
        "answer": "vasoconstriciton, increased, increased, mydriasis, increased",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a2 agonists leads to i____ of NE release, i____ of acetylcholine release, and i____ of insulin release",
        "answer": "inhibition, inhibition, inhibition",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "B1 agonists lead to t____, i____ lipolysis, i____ myocardial contractility, and i____release of renin",
        "answer": "tachycardia, increased, increased, increased",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "B2 agonists lead to v____, d____ peripheral resistance, b____, i____ muscle and liver glycogenolysis, i____ release of glucagon, and r____ uterine smooth muscle",
        "answer": "vasodilation, decreased, bronchodilation, increased, increased, relaxed",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "L-tyrosine is converted to L-dopa by t____ h____ which is the r____ l____ s____",
		"answer": "tyrosine hydroxylase, rate limiting step",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "L-tyrosine is converted to ____ and then to ____ and then to ____",
        "answer": "L-dopa, dopamine, norepinephrine",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tyrosine hydroxylase is s____ and there is n____ hydroxylation of other related amino acids",
        "answer": "specific, no",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "tyrosin hydroxylase is inhibited by ____ NE",
        "answer": "high",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dopamine B hydroxylase is found in ____ synaptic storage vesicles",
        "answer": "NE",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dopamine B hydroxylase cofactors are ____ and a____ acid",
        "answer": "O2, ascorbic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dopamine B hydroxylase is inhibited by disulfiram (Antabuse) which works by inhibition of a____ d____ that prevents the formation of acetic acid and produces an immediate hangover",
        "answer": "acetaldehyde dehydrogenase",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Phenethanolamine N-Methyltransferase is located in the a____ medulla and b____",
        "answer": "adrenal, brain",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Phenethanolamine N-Methyltransferase uses S____ as methyl donor",
        "answer": "SAM",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Phenethanolamine N-Methyltransferase converts ____ to ____",
        "answer": "NE, E",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "MAO is mainly found in the l____ and b____",
        "answer": "liver, brain",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "MAO is n____-specific and deaminates t____ and c____ and requires ____ as a cofactor",
        "answer": "non, tyramine, catecholamines, O2",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "MAO is mainly responsible for regulating i____ levels of E, NE (not in synaptic cleft)",
        "answer": "intraneuronal",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "MAO converts ____ to ____",
        "answer": "amine, aldehyde",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "COMT is found in l____ and k____ and requires ____ as a cofactor",
		"answer": "liver, kidneys, SAM",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "COMT is responsible for regulating e____ levels (in the synaptic cleft)",
        "answer": "extraneuronal",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Entacapone (Comtan) is available for ____ disease",
        "answer": "Parkinson's",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "COMT adds a ____ groupt to OH to turn it into ____",
        "answer": "CH3, OCH3",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Norepinephrine is oxidized by oxygen to q____",
        "answer": "quinone",
        "type": "text"
	},
    {
        "question": "l____ transmembrane residues are highly c____",
        "answer": "lipophilic, conserved",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Activation of all three B receptor subtypes result in activation of a____ c____ G____ which leads to increased conversion of ATP to cAMP leading to p____ of specific proteins",
        "answer": "adenylyl cyclase, s, phosphorylation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a1 adrenoceptor agonism activates G____ coupling protein which activates p____ C and produces ____ and ____ as second messengers. IP3 releases calcium and enzymes p____ their substrates = smooth muscle c____",
        "answer": "q, phospholipase, IP3, DAG, phosphorylate, contraction",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a2 adrenoceptor activates G____ leading to i____ of adenylyl cylcase instead of activation, resulting in inhibition of ____",
        "answer": "i, inhibition, NE",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a1 receptors agonism result in v____, r____ of gastrointestinal smooth muscle, s____ secretion",
        "answer": "vasoconstriction, relaxation, salivary",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "a2 receptor agonism result in i____ of NE and Ach release from autonomic nerves and p____ aggregation",
        "answer": "inhibition, platelet",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "B1 receptor agonism result in i____ cardiac rate and force, and r____ of GI smooth muscle",
        "answer": "increased, relaxation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "B2 receptor agonism result in b____, v____ and r____ of visceral SM",
        "answer": "bronchodilation, vasodilation, relaxation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "B3 receptor agonism result in a____",
        "answer": "adipolysis",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adrenergic agonists direct acting result in interaction at receptor ____",
        "answer": "agonist",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Indirect acting adrenergic agonists cause release of ____ like amphetamines and cocaine in the CNS",
		"answer": "NE",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "NE and E have limited clinical significance due to n____ actions and no oral bioavailability (intravenous)",
        "answer": "nonselective",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "E is used more clinically than NE in t____, trauma based h____, a____ reaction",
        "answer": "trauma, hypotension, allergic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Phenethanolamines (Phenylephrine) are used as d____, and h____ and is NOT a substrate for ____",
        "answer": "decongestant, hypotension, COMT",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "2-Arylimidazoline is a v____and is used as d____ and e____ drops",
        "answer": "vasoconstrictor, decongestant, eye",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "A____ (Iopidine) and b____ (Alphagan) is used in treatment of g____ and b____ is first line treatment for glaucoma",
        "answer": "Apraclonidine, brimonidine, glaucoma, brimonidine",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tizanidine (Zanaflex) is used as a m____ relaxant and is a ____ receptor and is used mostly in cerebral or spinal cord injury patient to reduce spastic motions",
        "answer": "muscle, a2",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Guanfacine (Tenex) and Guanabenz (Wytensin) is used as an a____ and A____",
        "answer": "antihypertensive, ADHD",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Methyldopa (Adomet) is CNS C____ acting, used for h____, and s____",
        "answer": "centrally, hypertension, sympatholytic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dopamine (B1) is used as post surgial c____ stimulant",
        "answer": "cardiac",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Main effect of B2 adrenergics is b____ and is used in a____ and chronic p____ diseases",
        "answer": "bronchodilation, asthma, pulmonary",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "SAR of B2 phenylethanolamine adrenergics must have 1 or 2 amines that are b____",
        "answer": "basic",
        "type": "text"
    }
]
